All my friends and welcome to exercise number 107.
And this exercise, we are going to implement the crew skills algorithm in Java and see its complexity,
its time, complexity and space complexity.
So we go to source faller algorithms and we create the new Java class called Kruskal-Wallis.
You can download the source codes from the resources folder under each question, under each exercise,
so we start by creating here the class
graph, or we can make it as like implementing it.
So class adds Willamette limit as edge implements compatible because we are going to compare to the
edges.
And it took considering me perimeter party perimeter type that perimeter for it as an object of edge.
If you need to learn more about that at the compatibles, the interfaces, the object and so on.
Please go back to that Java, our code Java course on Udemy, serrated 4.7 and moving up.
And we have many students, so please go and enroll and you can message us if you need any component
for it.
So intestacy equals or sort of this dimension and weight.
Now let's implement its method alpha plus enter implement comp compared to man compared to here, compare
ads and compare it compared to the method where determined that this is the weight minus the compare
at the weight.
OK.
This is class action now.
We need to make here
the union method.
Or I will make it as a class some union class subset, because it's good to make it this class because
I need the access and parents and the right.
OK, so.
After making this what I need to do, I need to create an instance from the previously created box,
so.
I will make here and in vertices and edges and edge
variable called edge.
Everything OK.
This is the edge of the edges of that edge and collecting the objects of.
Edge Typekit, no, it's made graph creation.
I will create through scale.
This is the value of this the constructor, and this is their variable view and variable in that we
are past as parameter in the constructors.
So the constructor, we are interrelated to vertices with the and the edges with a
and equal to new and edges at the next edges.
This is actually.
And fourth, and I equal to zero,
I think less than he and I plus plus
we assigned the ads at index equal to new at.
OK.
You are assigning this for it.
No, let's make this is inside the cross-code.
Then the inside this class, and this is the constructor of it.
OK, so let's make for this for you.
Let's make a and find method and took a parameter a subset subset.
And it took I wasn't sure what we will make with it.
We need to find if it is if the subset that index aid the verdant element does not equal to I, then
we will return and find it again using that catch.
If you need otherwise, we can make us and the scientists upset that didn't either bird and equal to
find method.
So how to do that?
We start by subset appendix I don't burden does not equal to.
I are checking.
Does not equal to I.
Then subset appendix I duck balanced equal to find method and we passed the subset and the subset Appendix
I the.
We will return subset that index by the bat.
OK.
This is how we find this subset.
Now let's check that union, so I will create here.
Avoid Union Method took in this parameter the subset subset as valuable and an X and Y variables as
predictors
and x root equal to find subsets and.
Yes, this is the substance
and x perspex and otherwise we need to make why route difficult to find the subsets?
And we pass one.
OK.
This is the accent right now.
If subsets Appendix X route and X x
x route dog rank less than subsets at Index Y route, the trunk is less there.
Then we use subsets the at Index X route, the parent
equal to Y, you know.
OK.
Else, if
subset subsets and things x route thought rank, we are comparing greater than subsets at Index Y a
route dot rank.
Then what we need to make, we need to assign the subset that index y route dot parent to assign the
parent variable or fit to X or
else what we need to make.
We need to make subsets at Index Y at all
equal parent.
Be equal to X root subsets.
Appendix X root the rank.
Increase it by yeah, I.
I know it may be confusing and the when I was studying the crew school algorithm, I found it one of
the complex algorithm encoding, but it's one of the simple grid, the algorithm that defined the shortest
path.
So I know everything it does.
It's sometimes hard to understand an algorithm or a code or anything, but I want from you to segment
this segment and partitioned your code and too many parts understand and and and memorize every part
and know why we are doing this.
So please go back to the animations for and try to understand the algorithm crucial and solve the exercises
and then try to implement it.
And don't worry, we are going to make a new section about the exercises also, and we continue it and
we apply that crew skill in many, many ways later on in the exercise by solving the real exercises
in university and in interviews.
So don't worry if you don't understand we are going to solve all your problems.
So let's continue and make that cross-code algorithm groups come and go.
It's a void method, and we start by making edge of a result Atalay equal to you and at with length
vertices now empty, equal to zero and equal to zero, and for loop and I can make it by equal to zero.
I think that does that vertices I plus plus what we will make.
We will make by starting by a result at index I equal to your edge.
Now let's sort that adjust here.
Or maybe.
I raised where I will use the phase package, Java, the GTA, and I will use the method sort edge,
no subset equal subset of things towards a new
subset of a and with length vertices force and I equal to zero or equal to zero because we have initialized
that and declared it and initialized it to zero.
Now I less than vertices and plus plus by
subset at subsets.
At index, there is substance at index i.e. equal to a new subset.
No.
Four in the equal to zero fee and less than vertices and
plus plus 50.
Subset of the index fee, the parent
equal to fee and subset at index fee to rank,
glittering equal to see, OK, this is initializing them position.
Now we need to make and and I.
Equal to zero now and we use the while loop.
So why?
Will tell us if e less than vertices is minus one?
Keep making these.
So if this condition is true, create an edge called next adds equal to new ads and the next edge says
this and next adds equal to edge at index i + + + + x equal to find subsets, but next at
the RC and M Y equals to find
subsets next.
Got this Danish?
This is what we have talked about in the previous video about making an X, X and Y, bypassing the
source at the first and this this thenation and the second way.
So we need to check if X does not equal to Y.
This is very logic.
Otherwise, it will become resolved at index p plus plus.
We make it equal to a next match and we call that union subset surpassing the subset X and Y, besting
a subset of these elements.
And we need to print that as, OK, if I'm equal to zero I less than E and plus plus I, we need to
print system the out print and the result at index ie the source plus.
That plus the result at Index I the destination.
And we need to print also the result wait.
So last year.
Plus result dot and index, by the way.
OK, so this is our algorithm.
Let's check that this algorithm by making that driver code public, static void, main string.
And
here I will make the edges and the vertices and vertices is I will make six and vertices and edges or
make it connections and edges.
OK, so I will create the graph here, graph g equal to you or.
People
go to school and they will pass the vertices and the best actress.
OK, now I would.
I will write down the edges of the vertices and the edges and the connection, the source, the nation
and the way.
And I would the video.
So here we are.
We have hanging and we are having the edge at index zero.
The source is equal to zero distinction one and weight equal to portions.
And this is the.
OK, I want from you to post the video and try to draw this graph and in order to see if you understand
that graph correctly or not.
And we pair we are going to call crucial algorithm this world, call the crucial algorithm and search
for their.
Distances and apply the crew skills that's announcing we have zero two one is four zero two one zero
two two four two two three is four two two four two five is four and two to four is for are arranging
and sorting them as a correct way.
And we find the path that it follows.
And connect all the elements as a three with a minimum weight.
OK, so there is another way to make it by using the Primm algorithm that we are going to learn in the
next video.
So let's let us talk about that crucial complexity so that cross-cultural complexity, complexity
that time complexity is of a crucibles algorithm is o to e lug b.
Okay, this is that time complexity.
This space complexity is oh two v because it depends on the vertices that we make and the crew skills
algorithm applications in order to to lay out electrical wiring and in computer network their land connection.
So we need to connect all the computers with the minimum connections and.